We'll start off this programming lesson in the wife, a --, so come over here, and the first
thing we need is a new message case for loading saved credentials.
So let's come here to our wi fi up messages.
And let's say wi fi app message.
Load saved credentials.
OK, now let's go to the C file.
And first, let's include.
Investor shortage.
But now let's go down to the global section here.
And now we'll create a section here for free art event group handle and status bits, which we'll use
to control the transition of events in our state machine where our message cases are handled in the
Wi-Fi application free autos task.
So let's say we find application event group handle.
And status bits.
And it's a static event group handle type and call it wi fi app event group.
And then the first bit is a constant.
And call it wi fi, a connecting.
Using saves creds.
Bit.
And say equals.
But zero.
Now, let's do another.
So say constant.
WI fi app.
Connecting from HTP server a bit.
Equals bit one.
And we'll use these bits to signify to the application whether we are connecting, using safe credentials
or connecting from the FTP server.
So let's go down to the Wi-Fi start function, no.
And Hugh will create an event group.
So let's say.
Create wi fi application event group.
And let's use our wi fi app, event group.
Equals.
X event group create.
OK.
And that creates the event group.
And if you follow this.
It'll take you to the event group's head of file from photos.
And on the frittatas website, you can read up on event bits and event groups and event bits are used
to indicate if an event has occurred or not, and an event group is a set of event bits and individual
bits within the event group, a reference by a bit number so they can always find out more information
about event groups from the theater's website.
OK, so let's go up.
And check out the bit definitions, and if you follow this one.
You'll see that impressive has these defined and esprit bit deaf studies.
So now let's head down to the free autos task.
And now here, let's create an instance of the event bits type.
And let's call it event bits.
And if you follow the event bits tape, you'll see that this is a type that holds event bits.
OK, so now let's just adjust our first message here to wi fi app message loads, say its credentials.
So now let's create a new case for it here by copying this one.
And pasting above.
All right, so now let's update the case.
And the message that's logged, and let's get rid of this, and let's say if.
Spin vs load state creds.
And if it returns true, meaning it loaded station credentials, then we'll ESP log.
Loaded station configuration.
And now he will call our Wi-Fi app Connect SDK function.
And now let's use our X event group set bits.
And pass over Wi-Fi app event group.
And set the connecting using saved crowds bit.
And then let's say else.
Then we'll ESB lug.
Unable to load station configuration.
Then we can say next.
Start the Web server.
And let's use wi fi apps send message.
And let's pass these start http server message you.
OK, so that takes care of this case for now.
Next, let's go down to the user requested disconnect case.
And here, let's call the app and voice clear state creds function.
Now, in the gut IP case, we need to save credentials disconnecting, connecting from the HTP server.
So here, let's say event bits.
Equals X event group get its.
And pass the wi fi app event group.
So let's say if event bids.
And wi fi app connecting using saved credit.
Then let's use X Event Group Clear Bits.
In past the event group and then past connecting using saved crowds bit.
And now I'll make a comment here.
Save state creds.
Only if connecting from HTTP server.
And not loaded from envious.
OK, in here, I'll also say clear the bits in case we want to disconnect.
And reconnect.
And then start again.
And now we can say else.
And call app and voice save star creds.
All right, so that takes care of this case for now.
Basically, we only want to save credentials if it's required.
All right.
So now let's go up to the connecting from HTP server case and Use X Event Group said it's.
And Passau Event Group.
And they are connecting from HTP server a bit.
All right, so if we connect from the Web server, we want to set this bit.
All right, so now let's go to the gut IP case.
And here will say if event bits.
And wi fi connecting from HTP server bit.
Then Will X event group clear bits.
In past soybean group and the connecting from HTP server bit.
OK, so now this event is accounted for.
OK, so next, let's go to the state disconnected case, and here we need to account for whether this
event occurred using Sade's credentials or not, so we'll need to check the event pitch and react accordingly.
So first, let's say event bits.
Equals X event group get bits in past the event group.
And then we'll say if event bids.
And wi fi connecting using saved creds bit.
Then we'll ESB lug.
That this case.
And attempt using saved credentials.
And then we'll x event group clear bits.
Passing the event group.
And wi fi app connecting using saved crowds bit.
OK, and then let's invest clear stay creds.
And then we'll say else if.
Event bits and wi fi app connecting from HTTP server bit.
Then we'll ESG lug.
That in our case here.
Attempt from the FTP server.
And then we'll need to clear the bits.
So let's just use this one.
And paste it and then change it to.
From HTP server a bit.
And now in here, we can call HTP Server Monitor.
Send message and pass HTP message, wi fi connect fail.
All right, so we only send that message if we're connecting from the Web server.
However, I do think we should expand both the HTP server and Wi-Fi application to handle the user requested
disconnect situation.
So now let's go to HTP server Duddridge and create a new Wi-Fi status for HTP.
Wi-Fi status disconnected?
And also create a new monitor message and call it 8TB message.
User disconnect.
And now go to HTP Server Dot, see?
And here, let's create a new case for our message.
So here we can use this one.
Now, update the case to user disconnect.
And the message.
Now we'll update the global Wi-Fi status to Wi-Fi status disconnected.
And now we can go back to the at sea.
And now let's go up.
All the way up here and create a new status bit.
And it's constant wi fi app user requested stay disconnected, but.
And it's a bit, too.
OK, so now let's go back to the free autos task state machine.
Another user requested state disconnect.
Right here.
Let's set the bit.
Or event group.
And it's a WI Wi-Fi app.
User requested.
Stay disconnect, but.
OK, so now let's go down to the disconnect case.
And say else if.
Event bits and wi fi app user requested stay disconnected.
Then ESB log.
From the disconnected case.
User requested disconnection.
And now ex event group Clear Bits.
Our event group.
And our state disconnect bit.
Next, let's let the Web server know using a CTP server monitor send message.
And it's to be message why fi user disconnect?
And this covers all of the obvious scenarios for the disconnected case, but there is one more case
where perhaps the access point is unavailable.
So let's say else.
ESP log.
That from our case.
Attempt failed.
Check Wi-Fi access point to availability.
All right.
So then I'll write a message for you here.
Adjust this case to your needs.
And maybe you want to keep trying to connect.
For example.
OK, now we can remove this message, send call, so get rid of that.
And now let's build.
OK, so then when you're ready, you can flush.
All right, and next, let's open the monitor.
And now we can connect to the ESP.
Right now, let's go to the Web page.
Right now, let's connect and start testing the new functions.
And now connect.
OK, great.
And from the monitor, we could see that the credentials were saved.
So now, of course, a reboot using the Enable button on the ESP.
OK, and you could do the same.
And now we see that we've automatically reconnected using our saved credentials.
Nice.
So now refresh the page.
And all looks great.
So now I'll disconnect my access point.
OK, so now the ECB is really trying to connect.
And after Max Re tries.
Our last statement is reached in the messages looked perfect.
OK, so it's the message right here.
All right, so now we could try another scenario.
And now I'll leave my access point disconnected and I'll reboot the ESP again.
Then on startup, if it fails to connect, the credentials should be deleted.
OK, so let's try it.
So just give me a moment.
OK, now the ECB is trying to connect, using saved credentials and retrying.
And retrying.
And after maximum retrace, the clear stay creds function is called exactly what we expected.
Great.
And here is the logged message.
And here is our corresponding message case with the clear state creds function is called.
All right, great.
So that's it for this lesson.
Let's continue in the next.